<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<root xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal" >
  <output>
    <content>
      <heading1>
        Basic Participation
      </heading1>

      <heading2>
        Making Posts
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
        A Post in an Online Group is an email to the group.
        Online Groups use email as a group collaboration medium. 
        All posts go to all participants and to the Messages area. 
        Posts can't be deleted.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        To make a post, either 
        address a new email to the Online Group's
        email address (shown on the Online Group's home page),
        or reply to a post you have received 
        via the Online Group.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        You can also make posts directly from this website.
        Use the "Start a new topic" link in the Messages area 
	of your Online Group, or scroll down to the "Add to the topic" 
	webform when viewing a topic.
      </paragraph>

      <heading2>
        Reading Posts
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
        You can read posts in an Online Group
        using your email client (Outlook, GroupWise&#8230;)
        or in the Group's Messages area on this website.
        The Messages area organises the posts into 
        Topics. You may be able to configure 
        your email software to display conversations
        (or "threads") as well.
      </paragraph>

      <heading2>
        Sharing Files
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
	You can share one or more files with the group by attaching 
	them to an email that you send to the group, or share a single 
	file with the group when you post a message from this website.
      </paragraph>

      <heading2>
        eMailing a Group Member Directly
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
        You can email another group member directly
        any time you like. Just click on their email address
        in an email or on this site. The jargon for this 
        it to "back-channel".
      </paragraph>
      
      <heading2>
        Remember!
      </heading2>
      <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
          all posts you make go to everyone in the group &#8212;
          make sure you aware of who is in the group and
          who can join or see into the group (described in the Membership
          and Roles section of the Online Group's Home page)
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          you can share files with the group by attaching one or more files to an 
          email that you send to the group, or by choosing one single file to share 
          when posting a message from this website
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          Online Groups work best when people participate
          and even better when you participate 
        <link url="../effective_participation">effectively</link>
        </listitem>
      </bulletlist>
    </content>
  </output>
</root>
