<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<root xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal">
  <output>
    <content>
      
      <heading1>
        Filtering Posts into a Folder
      </heading1>
      
      <!-- FOR WHEN WE HAVE ANCHORS
      <heading2>On this Page</heading2>
        
        <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
        <link url="#one">A Sense of Place</link>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
        <link url="#make">Make a folder with the group's name</link>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
        <link url="#move">Move all the posts you already have to the
        folder</link>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
        <link url="#auto">Make a filter to move new posts</link>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
        <link url="#links">Links</link>
        </listitem>
      </bulletlist>
        
        -->
      
      <heading2>
        A Sense of Place
      </heading2>
      
      <paragraph>
        Where is the group? People are in different places, communicating at
        different times. Is that a group? In an online group, we do not have the
        anchors of a physical place, there is no church, boardroom,
        cafe or classroom. There are no chairs, there is no white
        board. However there <em>is</em> a group.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        An online group is in our imagination, the place is created with words.
        The group's name has to do the work done by many atoms in a
        physical group.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        Yet those atoms are not the group. All groups have their reality in
        the imagination. Words, symbols and icons evoke the imagination. The
        use of symbols and words make the group what it is. The simple act of
        having all the posts in a folder with the group's name is one
        symbolic way to give the group a place.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        It is useful for the imagination and it is basic Inbox email
        management.
      </paragraph>
      
      <heading2>
        Make a folder with the Online Group's name
      </heading2>
      
      <paragraph>
        You can usually use the first part of the group's email address 
        (eg if the groups email address of the group is: "our_group@onlinegroups.co.nz"
        then use "our_group").
      </paragraph>
      
      <heading2>
        Move all the posts you already have to the folder
      </heading2>
      
      <paragraph>
        Either cut and paste them or use drag and drop.
      </paragraph>
      
      <heading2>
        Make a filter to move new posts
      </heading2>
      
      <paragraph>
        It is likely that your email program can move posts automatically into
        the folder. The term filtering is widely used for that. Some programs
        call it a "Rule" or a "Message Rule". Setting up
        filters is a useful skill to aquire. It is essential if you join a few
        groups. Filters can work for personal mail and also be set up to
        filter junk. Each email program has its own way of creating filters.
        Different versions of programs do it differently. It is useful to ask
        in the group for details about your program, but first check the
        following links:
      </paragraph>
      
      <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
          <link url="howtofilter.html">How to Filter with Various email Programmes</link>
        </listitem>
      </bulletlist>
      
      <heading2>
        Links on the Web
      </heading2>
      
      <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
          <link url="http://kb.indiana.edu/data/afaj.html?cust=1200" target=
            "_blank">In Microsoft Outlook 97, 98, and 2000, how do I set up
            rules to handle incoming mail?</link> 
        </listitem>
      </bulletlist>
      
      
    </content>
  </output>
</root>
