<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<root xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal">
  <output>
    <content>
      <heading1>
        Effective Participation
      </heading1>
      
      <paragraph>
        There are four simple guidelines for Effective Participation
        in Online Groups:
      </paragraph>
      
      <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
          <link url="#1">delete the emails</link>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <link url="#2">use accurate subject lines</link>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <link url="#3">delete the text of the previous messsage</link>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <link url="#4">use the group to share files</link>
        </listitem>
      </bulletlist>
      
      <heading2 id="1">
        Delete the Emails
      </heading2>
      
      <paragraph>
        You may receive a lot of email via your Online Group. 
        The point of this is to increase communication
        but to do this effectively. You should be able to tell 
        whether a post is relevant to you or not just by reading the 
        subject line. If it isn't, you can get a sense of what is 
        going on in the group without even reading it. Even if you 
        do open and skim read it, unless you want to respond or act on 
        the post, you can delete it. You can always go to the
        Topics area to find it again.
      </paragraph>
      
      <paragraph>
        Many people find it useful to keep 
        all of the posts in an email folder.
        You can even set up a rule or filter to put
        them there automatically.
        If you prefer, you can delete the emails 
        from your Inbox as you receive them and 
        read them in the Topics area when you 
        are ready.
      </paragraph>
      
      <heading2 id="2">
        Use Accurate Subject Lines
      </heading2>
      
      <paragraph>
        Stick to the topic described in the subject 
        line. If you are responding on the same topic, use the 
        same subject line. If you are starting a new topic, create
        a new email and give it an appropriate subject line.
        Look at the Topics area of your Online Group now to see
        how it organises posts into a readable sequence.
        You can configure some email clients to support this 
        (known as "threading") as well.
      </paragraph>
      
      <heading2 id="3">
        Delete the Text of the Previous Messsage
      </heading2>
      
      <paragraph>
        Delete the text of the post you are replying to.
        Keep your post as short and to-the-point as possible.
        The text is already in the Topics area. Quote from 
        the previous post minimally and clearly.
      </paragraph>
      
      <heading2 id="4">
        Use the Group to Share Files
      </heading2>
      
      <paragraph>
        You can share files with an Online Group in two ways:
      </paragraph>

      <bulletlist>
      	<listitem>
    	    when sending an email to the group, add one or more files 
    	    to your email as attachments
      	</listitem>
      	<listitem>
    	    when posting a message from this website, click the "Browse" 
          button under the "File" heading and choose one single file to 
    	    share with the group
      	</listitem>
       </bulletlist>

       <paragraph>
      	The files will be uploaded to the site, and a link to each file added
      	to your post. A list of the posts with attached files is clearly 
      	displayed at the top of the page when viewing a topic.
       </paragraph>
      
      <paragraph>
        Benefits of Sharing Files with the Group
      </paragraph>
      
      <numberedlist>
        <listitem>
          people can choose when they download files (rather than getting them whether they like it or not)
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          the group can build a single shared collection of files rather than each member having their own set of files that may be different from the shared set
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          the effort of maintaining an organised collection of files only needs to be done once, rather than by everyone in the group
        </listitem>
        
      </numberedlist>
      
      <heading2>Finer Points</heading2>
      
      <heading3>
        Sending Links
      </heading3>
      
      <paragraph>
        You can copy a link to a file or website
        and paste it into a post to an Online Group.
      </paragraph>
      
      <paragraph>
        Some links ("urls") will be broken into two 
        pieces by some email clients. To make them 
        work, join them back together by pasting the
        two parts into the "address" part of your Web browser
        one after the other.
      </paragraph>
      
      
      <heading3>eMail Etiquette</heading3>
      <paragraph>These guidelines apply to emails in Online
        Groups and to email use in general:</paragraph>
      
      <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
          never forward an email (or document) to a third person without
          the original sender's consent (unless the content is obviously 
          in the public domain)
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
          never send large file attachments without the recipient's consent
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
          never send a person's email address to others without their consent - 
          use "bcc:" (blind carbon copy), not "to:" or "cc:" when sending 
          an email to multiple recipients who don't know each other)
        </listitem>
      </bulletlist>
      
      <paragraph>Here are some resources on 
        the effective use of email:</paragraph>
      
      <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
          Kaitlin Duck Sherwood's classic
        <link url="http://www.webfoot.com/advice/email.top.html">
            Beginner&#39;s Guide to Effective Email</link>.
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
          <link url="http://kb.indiana.edu/data/adkc.html"
            target="_blank">What do BTW, FAQ, FYI, IMHO, RTFM,
            and other acronyms mean?</link> 
        </listitem>
        
        <listitem>
        <link url="http://www.help.mindspring.com/docs/006/emailheaders/emailheaders.php3"
            target="_blank">Email Headers explained</link>
        </listitem>
        
      </bulletlist>
      
    </content>
  </output>
</root>

