<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<html xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal"
  xmlns:metal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/metal"
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2002/06/xhtml2/">
  <head>
    <title>Design of Groups</title>
    <meta property="dc:created">March 2007</meta>
    <meta property="dc:publisher">OnlineGroups.Net</meta>
    <meta property="dc:rightsHolder">OnlineGroups.Net</meta>
    <meta property="dc:creator">Michael JasonSmith</meta>
    <meta property="dc:licence"/>
  </head>
  <body id="groupserver-admin-design">
    <section>
      <h>
        Design of Online Groups
      </h>
      <p>
        An online group is virtual.
        It exists in the imagination of the participants. 
        When people act on their belief that an online group exists, and 
        post to it, this strengthens the  participants' belief in the
        existence of the online group. 
        An online groups is more coherent when the participants have a 
        single  shared view of what the online group is. 
        To develop successful online groups, it is therefore important to
        clearly communicate what kind of a place the online group is, both 
        to the participants  and to non-participants. 
        The settings in the software, all actions taken by the owner, 
        participation coach and the administrator,  must be consistent 
        with this. 
        Once the group has been launched,the design should never be changed.
      </p>
      
      <p>
        The Design defines the purpose of the online group, and its main
        boundaries:
      </p>
      
      <dl>
        <di>
          <dt>Membership</dt>
          <dd>Who can be in the group and what their roles are.</dd>
        </di>
        <di>
          <dt>Participation Protocol</dt>
          <dd>What is ok in the online group.</dd>
        </di>
      </dl>
      
      <p>
        The Design must be based on an understanding of the nature and 
        requirements of the (real life) group that the Online Group is 
        for.
        If this understanding is not present, an assessment must be 
        carried out. 
        If the OnlineGroups.Net Consultant and Online Group Owner, 
        together have that understanding, then the documentation of  it 
        that will be  implicit in this Design will be sufficient 
        documentation. 
        It is important that the Design Elements are assessed carefully 
        against the criteria provided for each element as this will ensure 
        that the design is well-linked to the shared understanding of 
        the nature and requirements of the group.
      </p>
      <section id="name">    
        <h>Name</h>
        <p>
          The name is the most important design element of an Online 
          Group. 
          It embodies the essence of the group and, if it works, will 
          become a shared shorthand for all the participants know and 
          value about the group.
        </p>
        <p>    
          The name should be easy to say and to refer to in email. 
          It should be suitable for use in a url and an email address 
          (probably all in lower case).
          The name can have "full" and "short" versions.
        </p>
        <p>
          The criteria for a name are:
        </p>
        <dl>
          <di>
            <dt>Potency</dt>
            <dd>
              The name should be interesting and engaging so that it 
              communicates a lot of meaning.
              Double meanings and humour can be useful in generating names 
              that are catchy but not overdone.
            </dd>
          </di>
          <di>
            <dt>Brevity</dt>
            <dd>&#9786;</dd>
          </di>
          <di>
            <dt>Accuracy</dt>
            <dd>
              The name should encapsulate or evoke the people, the place,
              the purpose, the participation, and the passion.
            </dd>
          </di>
          <di>
            <dt>Fit</dt>
            <dd>
              The name must not clash with any other group.
            </dd>
          </di>
        </dl>
        <section class="note">
          <h>Hyphens and Underscores</h>
          <p>
            The Internet convention seems to be that underscores are a
            replacement for spaces and hyphens are a separator (perhaps 
            between set and member in set-member). 
            For online group names, either makes sense.
          </p>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="owner">
        <h>Owner</h>
        <p>
          Is it important that the participants know who convened
          the establishment of the Online Group. See 
          <a href="../roles/#owner">Roles in Online Groups</a>
          for more information.
        </p>
      </section>    
      <section id="real-life-group">
        <h>Real Life Group</h>
        <p>
          The Real Life Group is the group of people that the Online Group
          is for. 
          The group might or might not exist already. 
          It is important to distinguish the Real Life Group from the 
          Online Group as they are separate entities.
          The Real Life Group meets in the Online Group, and may also meet 
          face to face or via other media.
        </p>
        <p>
          The Real Life Group should be named in such a way that it can be used to 
          complete the statement "[OnlineGroupName] is an Online Group 
          for&#8230;"
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="purpose-satement">
        <h>Purpose Statement</h>
        <p>
          The purpose statement defines the reason for the existence of 
          the Online Group. 
          The purpose of the Online Group is different to the  purpose of
          the Real Life group. 
          purpose of the Online Group is usually to, in some way, enable 
          the Real Life Group to achieve its purpose. 
          The Purpose Statement must define how the Online Group will
          enable the Real Life Group to achieve its purpose.
          It must do so in a straightforward way that is compelling and 
          attractive to the group members.
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="membership-criterion">
        <h>Membership Criterion</h>
        <p>
          The Membership Definition is the most defined boundary that an 
          Online Group has. 
          It determines who can be in the group.
          The membership must be defined in such a way that 
          it can be implemented in an even-handed way in the future.
        </p>   
        <p>
          It is important that group participants know, not just who is 
          in the group at present, but who might join the group in future. 
          It is also important that participants know 
          that they may no longer meet the membership criterion in future, 
          for example if the membership is restricted to current 
          office-holders in a committee.
        </p>   
        <p>
          Membership is conditional on compliance with the Participation
          Protocol.
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="visibility">    
        <h>Visibility</h>
        <p>
          The boundaries of Online Groups are highly variable. 
          Groups can be very public, very private and have a number of 
          levels of privacy in between those. 
          It is important that the level of privacy is appropriate to the
          requirements for the group and that it is communicated very 
          clearly to the participants.
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="location">
        <h>Location</h>
        <p>
          All Online Groups are located in a site. 
          Project Owners with multiple Online Groups often have a site of
          their own.
          Where a new site is to be established, a Site Design is required. 
          Where the Online Group is to be located in a site that already 
          exists, or for which a Site Design has been completed, all that 
          is required is to name that site. 
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="participation-protocol">
        <h>Participation Protocol</h>
        <p>
          The Participation Protocol defines the secondary boundary for 
          the Online Group. 
          It defines "what is OK" in the Online Group. 
          The Membership Definition (the primary boundary) is conditional 
          on compliance with the Participation Protocol.
        </p>
      </section>
      <section id="encouraged-participation">
        <h>Encouraged Participation</h>
        <p>
          The Encouraged Participation items provide a chance to name 
          the particular kinds of participation that are expected to 
          achieve the purpose for the Participants and the Owner.
        </p>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</html>

