<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<html xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal"
  xmlns:metal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/metal"
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2002/06/xhtml2/"
  metal:use-macro="context/@@groupserver_layout/page">
  <head>
    <title>Online Groups Participation Guide: Keeping Track of Conversations</title>
    <meta property="dc:created">February 2008</meta>
    <meta property="dc:publisher">OnlineGroups.Net</meta>
    <meta property="dc:rightsHolder">OnlineGroups.Net</meta>
    <meta property="dc:creator">Alice Murphy</meta>
    <meta property="dc:licence"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" 
      href="/Presentation/Tofu/Common/css/xhtml2-globalstyle.css"/>
  </head>
  <body id="help-participation-guide-keep-track"
    tal:define="site context/Scripts/get/division_object;
      siteName site/title_or_id">
    <section>
      <h>Keeping Track of Conversations</h>
      <p>
        Often, you do not wish to read every post in an online group, but you do
        want to keep track of the conversation. The simplest way to do this is 
        to glance at the subject and sender information, and then 
        <a href="#delete-the-emails">delete the emails</a>. You can usually tell
        what is being discussed in the group without reading every post, 
        especially if members 
        <a href="../contribute/#contribute-write-good-subject-lines">write good subject lines</a>.
        You can always go to the web interface to read the conversations in 
        detail. If you prefer not to use this method, you can 
        <a href="#filter-the-emails">filter the emails</a> or 
        <a href="#topic-digest">use the topic digest</a> or 
        <a href="#web-feed">a web feed</a>
        to keep track of the conversations.
      </p>
      <section id="contents">
        <nl>
          <li><a href="#delete-the-emails">Delete the Emails</a></li>
          <li><a href="#filter-the-emails">Filter the Emails</a></li>
          <li><a href="#topic-digest">Use the Topic Digest</a></li>
          <li><a href="#web-feed">Use a Web Feed</a></li>
        </nl>
      </section>

      <section id="delete-the-emails">
        <h>Delete the Emails</h>
        <p>
          You may receive a lot of email via your Online Group. The point of 
          this is to increase communication but to do so effectively. You 
          should be able to tell whether a post is relevant to you or not just
          by reading the subject line. If it isn't relevant, you have still
          gained information about what is going on in the group. If you do 
          open and skim or read the email, you can then delete it, unless you 
          want to respond to or act on it. You don't need to worry about 
          finding it again later, because you can always go to the Topics area 
          of the group to locate it.
          </p>
        <section id="delete-the-emails-advantages">
          <h>Advantages</h>
          <nl>
            <li>
              You can keep track of what is going on in the group while only 
              reading emails that are relevant to you.
            </li>
            <li>
              You do not have to manage a lot of stored email.
            </li>
          </nl>
        </section>
        <section id="delete-the-emails-disadvantages">      
          <h>Disadvantages</h>
          <nl>
            <li>
              To read a message again later, you must visit the website.
            </li>
          </nl>
        </section>
        <section id="delete-the-emails-how">
          <h>How To</h>
          <ol>
            <li>
              Look at the subject line and sender of the email message, and 
              decide whether or not it is relevant to you.
            </li>
            <li>
              If the message is relevant to you, open and read the email.
            </li>
            <li>
              Delete the email.
            </li>
            <li>
              To read the message again later, visit the Topics area of the
              group and navigate or search for the relevant topic or post.
            </li>
          </ol>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section id="filter-the-emails">
        <h>Filter the Emails</h>
        <p>
          Some people find it useful to keep all of the posts from an online
          group in a separate email folder. You can even set up a rule or filter 
          to put them there automatically. If you prefer, you can delete the 
          emails from your Inbox as you receive them and read them in the Topics 
          area when you  are ready. 
        </p>
        <section id="filter-the-emails-advantages">
          <h>Advantages</h>
          <nl>
            <li>
              Group posts are kept separate from the rest of your email.
            </li>
          </nl>
        </section>
        <section id="filter-the-emails-how">
          <h>How To</h>
          <ol>
            <li>
              In your email client, create a folder with the same name as the
              group.
            </li>
            <li>
              Create a rule or filter to put all messages from the group email 
              address into that folder.
            </li>
          </ol>          
        </section>
      </section>

      <section id="topic-digest">
        <h>Use the Topic Digest</h>
        <p>
          <span tal:content="siteName" /> can send you an email 
          summarising the top ten topics in the group. For each topic, the 
          title, number of posts, date of the last post, and location of the 
          topic on the web are displayed. The digest is sent once per day so 
          long as there is activity in the group, or once per week if there is 
          no activity in the group.
        </p>
        <section id="topic-digest-advantages">
          <h>Advantages</h>
          <nl>
            <li>
              You will not receive more than one email per day from each online
              group that you have set to digest.
            </li>
            <li>
              Based on the topic title and the number of posts, you can decide 
              whether a topic is of interest <em>before</em> reading any of the 
              posts in that topic.
            </li>
          </nl>
        </section>
        <section id="topic-digest-disadvantages">      
          <h>Disadvantages</h>
          <nl>
            <li>
              If you are interested in a topic, you must visit the website before
              you can read any of the posts in that topic.
            </li>
            <li>
              You may not see some posts for up to 24 hours after they are
              posted.
            </li>
          </nl>
        </section>
        <section id="topic-digest-how">
          <h>How To</h>
          <div id="change-message-notification-digest-content">Loading&#8230;</div>
        </section>
      </section>

      <section id="web-feed">
        <h>Use a Web Feed</h>
        <p>
          <span tal:content="siteName" /> provides a web feed for 
          all posts in a group. You can subscribe to the
          <a class="weblink"
            href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_feed">web feed</a>
          of posts, and then your
          <a class="weblink"
            href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feed_reader">feed reader</a>
          will show you the most recent posts in the group.
        </p>
        <section id="web-feed-advantages">
          <h>Advantages</h>
          <nl>
            <li>
              You will be notified as soon as a post has been added to the group.
            </li>
            <li>
              You can read the full text of a post directly in your feed reader, 
              without needing to visit the website.
            </li>
          </nl>
        </section>
        <section id="web-feed-disadvantages">
          <h>Disadvantages</h>
          <nl>
            <li>
              You must have either an internet browser capable of functioning as a
              feed reader, or an account with a web-based feed reading service.
            </li>
          </nl>
        </section>
        <section id="web-feed-how">
          <h>How To</h>
          <div id="reading-web-feeds-content">Loading&#8230;</div>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>

    <tal:block metal:fill-slot="javascript">
      <script type="text/javascript">
        jQuery.noConflict()
        jQuery(document).ready( function () {
            jQuery("#change-message-notification-digest-content").load("/help/manual/ #groupserver-changing-your-message-notification-settings-instructions", {}, fix_html);
            jQuery("#reading-web-feeds-content").load("/help/manual/ #groupserver-reading-messages-using-web-feeds-instructions", {}, fix_html);
        });
        var fix_html = function (responseText, textStatus, XMLHttpRequest) {
          jQuery(this).find("a").each(function(){jQuery(this).attr('href', '/help/manual'+jQuery(this).attr('href'));});
        }
      </script>
    </tal:block>

  </body>
</html>

