<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal">
  <output>
    <content>
      <heading1>
        Benefits of Online Groups
      </heading1>
      <heading2>
        Benefits of Collaboration
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
        Working, learning and sharing knowledge in 
        groups is more effective than working as isolated 
        individuals in complex and dynamic situations.
        Other tasks require head-down time.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        The key Benefits of Collaboration are:
      </paragraph>
      <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
          you get more done &#8212; you achieve greater success with work and 
          learning goals
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          you have more fun - you have less stress and more enjoyment
        </listitem>
      </bulletlist>
      <heading2>
        Benefits of Collaborating Online 
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
        Collaborating Online is like having a brain 
        for a group. It enables to group to "think"
        together, even when its members are distributed across 
        organisations, space and time. It also supports  
        instant recall of past conversations and work done
        at any time.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        When you Collaborate Online:</paragraph>
      <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
          you can participate at your own time, your own 
          place and your own pace &#8212; you decide when you want to 
          participate and when you do, you can quickly catch up on what 
          the others have done in the meantime, make your contribution
          and then move on to the next thing
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          everything is recorded &#8212; the communications 
          made in the group are organised either in structured 
          repositories or in systems with an adaptable structure, 
	  like email threads
        </listitem>
      </bulletlist>
      <heading2>
        Benefits of Effective Participation
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
        Participation in an Online Group gets easier as you use it.
        Your participation encourages others to participate 
        and makes the benefits of collaboration more available.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        Thoughtful, asynchronous, text-based group discussions,
        especially where trust is developed in the group, 
        can be highly effective for solving complex problems 
        and getting work done.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        Effective Participation increases the "signal",
        reduces the "noise" and increases the efficiency
        with which a group can function together.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        As group members get to know each other 
        and trusting working relationships develop, 
        a group can deeply explore issues and 
        collaborate to everyone's advantage.
      </paragraph>
    </content>
  </output>
</root>
