<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<html xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal"
  xmlns:metal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/metal"
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2002/06/xhtml2/">
  <head>
    <title>
      Online Groups Participation Guide: Benefits of Online Participation
    </title>
    <meta property="dc:created">March 2008</meta>
    <meta property="dc:publisher">OnlineGroups.Net</meta>
    <meta property="dc:rightsHolder">OnlineGroups.Net</meta>
    <meta property="dc:creator">Dan Randow</meta>
    <meta property="dc:licence"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" 
      href="/Presentation/Tofu/Common/css/xhtml2-globalstyle.css"/>
  </head>
  <body id="help-participation-guide-benefits">
    <section>
      <h>Benefits of Online Participation</h>
      <section>
        <h>Benefits of Collaboration</h>
        <p>
          Working and learning in groups is more fun, and you get more done. 
          Complex problems are often more easily solved by a team, than an 
          individual, especially when the team is made up of people with diverse 
          points of view. People maintain the expertise they bring to teams, by 
          associating with others who share their expertise. Work is more fun and 
          interesting when you have people to swap notes, and toss ideas around 
          with.
        </p>
      </section>
      <section>
        <h>Benefits of Collaborating Online</h>
        <p>
          It's hard to beat collaborating in the same place at the same time, 
          especially when you want to hear from everyone in the group. It's 
          often difficult, however, to meet face-to-face. People may have to 
          travel, but even if they don't, it's often hard to find a time when 
          everyone is available. And face-to-face, each person can only 
          participate in one conversation at a time. The larger the group, the 
          worse these problems get.
        </p>
        <p>
          The obvious benefit of collaborating online is that you can 
          participate from wherever you like. There is no travelling required. 
          Collaborating online, however, also means that people don't have to 
          participate at the same time.
        </p>
        <dl>
          <di>
            <dt>No scheduling problems or interruptions</dt>
            <dd>Each person can participate at the time that suits them.</dd>
          </di>
          <di>
            <dt>Hold concurrent conversations</dt>
            <dd>
              People can participate in multiple conversations at the same time.
            </dd>
          </di>
          <di>
            <dt>Take your time</dt>
            <dd>
              People can take the time they want to reflect on and add to 
              conversations.
            </dd>
          </di>
          <di>
            <dt>Meet in larger groups</dt>
            <dd>
              By breaking into sub-groups, large groups can easily meet online.
            </dd>
          </di>
          <di>
            <dt>In-built record-keeping</dt>
            <dd>
              All conversations online form a searchable archive that can be 
              accessed at any time in the future.
            </dd>
          </di>
        </dl>
        <p>
          Online collaboration does have disadvantages compared with 
          face-to-face. There is no voice tone or body language, making it 
          much less immediate and dynamic. These disadvantages cannot be 
          overcome, but they can be mitigated by effective participation.
        </p>
      </section>
      <section>
        <h>Benefits of Effective Participation</h>
        <p>
          Taking time to communicate your ideas clearly makes them easier to
          find. Others are more likely to pay attention to you, and more likely 
          to respond thoughtfully.
        </p>
      </section>
    </section>
  </body>
</html>

