<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<root xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal">
  <output>
    <content>
      <heading1>
        How Online Groups Work
      </heading1>
      <paragraph>
        There are three key things that make Online Groups work:
      </paragraph>
      <bulletlist>
        <listitem>
          technology &#8212; basic technology that enables email to be 
          used as a group collaboration medium and files to be shared 
          online</listitem>
        <listitem>
          boundaries &#8212; clearly defined membership and participation 
          protocols</listitem>
        <listitem>
          participation &#8212; the more you use them, the better they 
          work</listitem>
      </bulletlist>
      
      <heading2>
        How the Online Groups Technology Works
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
        Online Groups are based on an Internet eMail List Server.
        You may have used other List Servers or "Email Groups" such as 
        Yahoo! Groups.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        Each Online Group has an email address. The basic functioning 
        of the Online Group is that all "posts" (emails) sent to
        the Online Group's email address are emailed to all
        members of the group.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        Posts made to Online Groups also appear in the "Messages" section 
        of the Online Group in this website. Posts can 
        not be deleted from the Messages area.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        You can send file attachments to Online Groups. The files will 
        be added to your post as links. Members of the group can retrieve
	the files through these links if they choose.
      </paragraph>

      <heading2>
        How the Boundaries of Online Groups Work
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
        Online Groups work best when trust develops in the group.
        Trust develops best in Online Groups when the purpose, membership
        and participation protocols are clearly defined and maintained. The 
        membership and participation protocol must be strictly 
        maintained by the members and the service provider.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        In the case of Online Groups, the service provider
        is OnlineGroups.Net. OnlineGroups.Net maintains
        the privacy of participation in Online Groups.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        It is also critical that Participants in Online Groups 
        maintain the boundaries. In particular, in a private 
        Online Group, the privacy of the other members' posts 
        must be respected.
      </paragraph>
      
      <heading2>
        How Participation makes Online Groups Work
      </heading2>
      <paragraph>
        The technology and boundaries create the conditions where 
        online collaboration can take place. It is only when people
        actually use it, that the potential can be realised. There 
        is only any value in posting, if others reply. Participants have 
        to get the ball rolling and contribute to its momentum.
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph>
        Each post that is made demonstrates to the participants that 
        the Online Group exists. It communicates to the others
        that the Online Group is a place where knowledge is shared - 
        that if they share knowledge, then others will share back.
      </paragraph>
    </content>
  </output>
</root>
