<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<root xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal">
  <output>
    <content
      tal:define="site context/Scripts/get/division_object;
        authenticated python:'Authenticated' in user.getRolesInContext(site)">
      
      <heading1>
        Frequently Asked Questions
      </heading1>
      
      <faqs>
        <faq>
          <question>
      	    How do I find the email address for my Online Group?
          </question>
          <answer>
            The email address for your Online Group is on the Online Group's 
            home page on this site. Go to the <a href="/groups">Groups section</a>
            and then click the link to your Online Group.
          </answer>
        </faq>

        <faq>
          <question>
            I did not receive an email notifying me about my Online Group. What 
            do I do?
          </question>
          <answer>
            If you are reading this, you do not need that email. Please make 
            sure that your email address(es) is/are registered to your profile 
            by visiting your 
            <a tal:attributes="href python:'/contacts/%s/useremail' % user.getId()"
              tal:omit-tag="python:not(authenticated)">Edit Email Settings page</a>.
            Then simply try posting to your Online Group.
          </answer>
        </faq>

        <faq>
          <question>
            I sent an email to my Online Group and it hasn't appeared in the 
            Topics section of my Online Group.
          </question>
          <answer>
      	    First, check that the message was sent to the Online Group. If it 
      	    was, you will have received a copy of your own message. It will have
      	    a shortened version of the Online Group name in the subject line 
      	    (e.g. [groupname]). If you got the message and it is not in the 
      	    Topics section of the Online Group, please contact us. If you did 
      	    not receive the message, check to make sure the email address you 
      	    sent it to was correct. Also check that the email address you sent 
      	    the message from is registered to your profile. You can do this by 
      	    going to your 
            <a tal:attributes="href python:'/contacts/%s/useremail' % user.getId()"
              tal:omit-tag="python:not(authenticated)">Edit Email Settings page</a>.
            You can change your email address(es) there if neccessary.
          </answer>
        </faq>

        <faq>
          <question>
      	    How do I change my email address?
      	  </question>
          <answer>
      	    Go to your
            <a tal:attributes="href python:'/contacts/%s/' % user.getId()"
              tal:omit-tag="python:not(authenticated)">profile page</a>.
            Click the Edit Email Settings link in the menu. On this page you can
            add or remove email addresses. To add an email address, type your 
            email address into the 'New Address' field and click 'Add Address'. 
            To remove an email address, click the button to the left of it and 
            then click 'Remove Address'.
          </answer>
      	</faq>
        
        <faq>
          <question>
      	    When I send an email to my Online Group, I receive an email
      	    telling me I am not a member of the group even though I am.
      	  </question>
          <answer>
      	    It may be that your email is configured such that your outgoing
      	    messages are sent from a different email address to the one that you
      	    use to receive incoming messages. The difference may be slight, but
      	    it will still mean that you cannot post to Online Groups via email.
      	    Very carefully, compare the email address mentioned in the reply you
      	    received ("2. You have not specified the email address &lt;...&gt; 
      	    on the site...") with the email addresses on your 
            <a tal:attributes="href python:'/contacts/%s/useremail' % user.getId()"
              tal:omit-tag="python:not(authenticated)">Edit Email Settings page</a>.
            If the email address mentioned in the email is not listed there, 
            add it (see "How do I change my email address?" above).
          </answer>
        </faq>
        
        <faq>
          <question>
      	    On my 'Edit Email Settings' page, what does 'Default Email Delivery'
      	    mean?
      	  </question>
          <answer>
	          If you tick the box next to one of your email addresses and click 
	          'Add to Default', you will receive posts from all your Online Groups
	          at that address unless you specify otherwise.
          </answer>
        </faq>

        <faq>
          <question>
            How do I change my settings so that messages from one or more 
            particular groups are delivered to an email address that is not in 
            my list of default addresses?
          </question>
      	  <answer>
      	    View your profile page and click the 'Edit Email Settings' link. 
      	    Under the heading 'Group Email Delivery Settings', find the group(s)
      	    for which that you wish to change delivery settings and click 
      	    'Change' on the line beginning 'Email Setting:'. Choose the 
      	    'Specific Address or Addresses' option and check the box next to the
      	    email address(es) at which you wish to receive the messages from 
      	    this group.
          </answer>
        </faq>
      </faqs>
      
    </content>
  </output>
</root>
