<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<root xmlns:tal="http://xml.zope.org/namespaces/tal">
  <output>
    <content>
      
      <heading1>
        Frequently Asked Questions
      </heading1>
      
      <faqs>
        <faq>
          <question>How do I find the email address for my Online Group?
          </question>
          <answer>
            The email address for your Online Group is on the Online Group's main page on this site.
            Go to the Groups section and then click the link to your Online Group.
          </answer>
        </faq>
        <faq>
          <question>
            I did not receive an email notifying me about my Online Group. What do I do?
          </question>
          <answer>
            If you are reading this, you do not need that email. Please make sure that your email 
            address(es) is(are) specified correctly on your Participant Details page ("Your Details").
            Then simply try posting to your Online Group.
          </answer>
        </faq>
        <faq>
          <question>
            I sent an email to my Online Group and it hasn't appeared in the 
            Messages section of my Online Group.
          </question>
          <answer>First check that the message was sent to the Online Group. 
            If it was, you will have received a copy of your own message. 
            It will have a shortened version of the Online Group name in the
            subject line (e.g. [groupname]).
            If you got the message 
            and it is not in the Online Group's messages folder, contact us.
            If you did not receive the message, check to make sure the address 
            you sent it to was correct. 
            Also check that the email address you sent the message from is 
            correct by going to your <link tal:attributes="url string:../../contacts/${user/getId}">Participant
              Details (Your Details)</link> page. 
            You can change your email address(es) there if neccessary.
          </answer>
        </faq>
        <faq>
          <question>How do I change my email address?</question>
          <answer>Go to your <link tal:attributes="url string:../../contacts/${user/getId}">Participant
              Details page (Your Details)</link>. On this page you can add or remove email address(es). 
            To add an email address type your new email address in to the 'Add an Email Address' field and click 'Add'. 
            To remove an email address, tick the 'Remove' box and click 'Update Email'.
          </answer></faq>
        
        
        <faq>
          <question>When I post to my Online Group, it tells me
            I am not a member of the group but I am.</question>
          
          <answer>It may be that you have your email settings 
            configured to your email coming from a different email 
            address to the one that you use to receive email. The difference
            may be slight but it will mean that you cannot post (send email to) 
            Online Groups. If this is the case, go to your 
          <link tal:attributes="url string:../../contacts/${user/getId}">Participant
              Details page (Your Details)</link>, add the second email address and 
            set "send email to this address" off so that you don't get two of every email.
          </answer>
        </faq>
        
        <faq>
          
          <question>On 'Participant Details', what does 'Send email to this Address' mean?</question>
          
          <answer>If you tick the 'Send email to this Address' box
            and click 'Update Email', you will receive all 
          <link url="../../groups/index.xml">Online Group</link> emails at this address. 
            Other Candidates in your Online Groups will also be able 
            to email you at that address from your Participant Details page.
          </answer>
        </faq>
        
        <faq>
          
          <question>On 'Participant Details', why would I switch
            'Send email to this Address' off?</question>
          
          <answer>Some people have their email settings configured 
            to show their email coming from a different email 
            address to the one that they use to receive email. The difference
            may be slight but it will mean that you cannot post (send email to) 
            Online Groups. If this is the case, add the second email address and 
            set "send email to this address" off so that you don't get two of every email.
          </answer>
        </faq>
      </faqs>
    </content>
  </output>
</root>
